<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: data science | Data nerds around the globe]]></title>
  <link href="http://datanerds.org/blog/categories/data-science/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://datanerds.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-29T23:55:22+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://datanerds.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sergii Khomenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data nerds: Intro]]></title>
    <link href="http://datanerds.org/blog/2014/01/18/data-nerds-intro/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T23:46:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://datanerds.org/blog/2014/01/18/data-nerds-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/datasci_skills_mosaic.png"></p>

<p>So community, like one smart guy said recently: &ldquo;If you want to use some nice technology, use it now&rdquo;.
If you like something, you need actually to start pushing it forward. I do like data science, machine learning and
other amazing  things, that help you to understand data, so I&rsquo;d like to commit into that field.</p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="mooc-knowledge-sharing-and-other-nice-things">MOOC, knowledge sharing and other nice things</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start with a problems, or why do I start something here. Since I moved to Munich I was
really inspired by local community. We always talking about current global view of information,
And it&rsquo;s completely true, honestly nowadays we have the best ever time to learn something new, just open
a browser and start learning your dream topic from professionals. With maturing of MOOC(Massive Open Online Courses)
it was never so easy to start learning something completely new.</p>

<p>Yes, of course, it&rsquo;s a good point to start, but you need more. Even when you have some ideas to discuss with
other like-minded people, so it&rsquo;s another stage, to have other people to discuss with, yes, you could do it online,
but if you could meet people in face it&rsquo;s even more exiting.</p>

<h2 id="tldr">TL;DR</h2>
<p>So the main idea behind this website is to build online representation of User Groups.
Nothing about actually building community, but more about a collaborative space where people
could easily share everything exciting about data science, machine learning and other data-related thoughts.</p>

<p>Hence, I&rsquo;m going to share here announcements on data-related events, share nice videos and other interesting things
on topics described above. Everyone is invited to send a pull-request to share the knowledge with community.</p>

<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ol>
  <li><a href="http://coffeenco.de/articles/community_is_future.html">Alex P&rsquo;s blog: Community is future!</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://tomtunguz.com/data-science-demystified/">Using Data To Demystify Data Science</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
